Yoonsie Kim

571-551-9067 Arlington, VA yoonsie.kim@gmail.com <u>linkedin.com/in/yoonsiekim</u>

Web developer turned product manager with 5 years of product development experience. Skilled in leading customer discovery interviews, increasing customer acquisition, and driving revenue for content creation, financial services, and education products.

Experience

Product Manager

Class

Remote
2021 – Present

As one of the first product hires at a B2B EdTech startup (\$100M Series B), led a team of 30+ engineers and designers in building out an engaging and scalable learning platform on Zoom

- Improved sales conversion rate and unblocked 30% of revenue targets by launching a proctoring tool, collaborative whiteboard functionality, course templating, and screen-sharing enhancements for pilot customers
- Led product strategy and roadmap definition with stakeholders, including building out a strategy for a new corporate vertical comprising Fortune 500 customers
- Saved the product team 10+ hours of manual work a week by streamlining the creation and management of user stories

Senior Product Consultant / Product Owner

Remote

Attain (now Maximus)

2020 - 2021

Owned the full product lifecycle for a financial services client to build a cloud-based case management application from scratch to replace a costly manual documentation process

- Led Agile team of 12 engineers, designers, business analysts to launch a document review workflow, decreasing time-to-review by 80% and leading to renewals for a \$115M contract
- Leveraged wireframes and proof of concepts to test hypotheses and drive priorities, including a Outlook email integration which would decrease scheduling time 95%

Senior Product Consultant / Product Owner

Reston, VA

Macedon Technologies

2017 - 2020

Built B2B CRM, real estate, onboarding, recruiting software products for customers and received a CEO-recognized award

- Interviewed customers and launched product iteration, reducing the time to log opportunities and prospects for a custom CRM application by 95%
- Leveraged SQL to identify a 5 minute core workflow affecting 80% of users, drove interviews to build a solution that would reduce the time to 15 seconds or less
- Led cross-functional team of 20+, identified cross-stream dependencies, and strategically prioritized work to decrease dependencies and reduce a 3 hour launch time to 30 minutes

Skills

- Product strategy, roadmapping, data analysis, competitive analysis, prioritization, wireframing, prototyping, Figma, Balsamiq, B2B SaaS product management
- Skilled in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, python, SQL, Atlassian JIRA, Confluence

Education

University of Rochester, B.A. Digital Media Studies-Computer Science, 3.8/4.0 | Rochester, NY